I would challenge the assumption that
stack PRs are less valuable in a world
where AI is generating the code because
I think if anything what we've seen is
that especially for like background
agents if you just kind of let them run
wild the result is you get multi,000line
unintelligible PRs it will be
increasingly important to have those
changes be understandable and digestible
by the humans that that need to check
it. So we built a graphite MCP. A lot of
our our customers are now actually
having their agents create stack PRs
precisely because it makes them easier
to review. On the other side,
[music]
the agents when they do a long work, if
you think of stack as a way for you to
continue working while you are
submitting stuff to review, is kind of
the core of it. Actually, these sort of
agents are a great example of that
because they don't want to wait and you
want to be able to review their work
incrementally and and I guess probably
there will be interfaces of once they
did submit something if there was
substantial correction in the review
they might kind of revert back to that
point and continue the work from there.
Uh which is something that humans will
probably be quite uh annoyed uh at
doing.
>> Exactly. And I think the the
revertability piece is another good
point there of like having you know
having like you know smaller you know
smaller pieces and and like a clear
history I think enables you to like more
easily figure out like where was what
was the change that that introduced this
problem like lets you roll back more
precisely like there's a lot of benefits
there to you know to having your agents
work in in smaller pieces and stacking
like a fantastic workflow uh to to
enable them to do that. Uh the second
point that I I wanted to make though was
that I I think a lot of folks like
really uh kind of get stuck on the idea
of like code review being the only value
of code review being this validation
step. And I think that that's that's
certainly you know one of the main
benefits of it. But I think the the
other piece, you know, the other two
pieces I'd say that are often missed of
this is that uh I think code review is
is also a great is also super important
in like sharing like sharing knowledge
across the team of uh helping you know
helping other engineers understand like
what is you know what is actually you
know going out to production what is
changing. Uh it's also a great moment of
teaching where you know where you f you
get a lot of feedback and um you you're
able to you're able to like improve u
the way that you're approaching
approaching your projects. So um those
two you know certainly the there's like
the validation quality piece u I think
AI can can take on but I think the the
latter two um are actually you know more
important than ever in many ways because
you know you have now if if even the
engineer who's like authoring the PR
doesn't fully understand the change like
you know I think there's it's all the
more important that you have you have a
moment to where you know where you know
you walk through everything and um you
can clearly communicate like what is
changing in the codebase
Similarly, I think having you know
sharing that with others uh you know
teaching others like what is what is
good about this change and what is not
uh like what what learnings they want to
apply and um and also having a moment
then to like feed any any like systemic
things back into uh into the the
reviewer and give it more more rules for
the future of what it should or
shouldn't look at like that piece is is
really important. So I think that those
you certainly [clears throat] the
validation you know code the purpose of
code review I think will shift over of
human review at least like will will
shift from validation you know more to
the the like you know pedagogy and and
you know knowledge sharing pieces. But I
I do think that those you know those two
are fundamentally you know I think
arguably more important in in terms of
like why we do code review today than
than the validation pieces anyways.
>> Yeah. Interesting. So, I guess you're
you're
>> we're going to jump into the second half
of our conversation. But first, a quick
shout out to AI Native DevCon. Two days
of hands-on sessions, deep dives, and
honest conversations about what it means
to build AI native software November
18th and 19th in New York, or join
virtually from anywhere. Tickets and
details at a native.io/devcon.
See you there. describing a a reality in
which maybe the um I guess the code
review that is fully automated. You
might eventually want to consume that as
a natural part of the of the agentic
development. It's a it's a it's a point
in time in which it is done in a
different system and needs to come back
to you. That's a that's maybe a hiccup.
Maybe they call into graphite through
that MCP not just to open the poll
request but to actually run the review
and kind of get the results. Um but but
then the I guess you mentioned two
things that are maybe long-term
relevant. One is the notion of a stacked
PR even if it is whether it is or isn't
reviewed incrementally just as a as a as
a means of demarcation of different
points in time. And second is uh as a
means of review of work that's been done
to be able to get guidance uh and to
provide guidance uh on what's there sort
of learn and guide uh the AI. I guess in
that context you probably would at some
point would have to veer away from
reviewing the code and reviewing some
analysis of the code, right? Because
it's just a it's a it's an unpleasant uh
uh future to imagine one in which all we
do is is uh is read code uh and uh and
review and kind of comment and nitpick
on it. Does that sound about right? Like
you're going to need some summaries or
sort of a uh reviews of the changes. Is
that a is that a likely future? Yeah, I
I mean I think the the framework that
that we talk about internally here is
that uh I think we we see three steps in
in the process and like the evolution of
of engineering and and code review as a
product of that like the first the first
step uh which I think we're we're
somewhat moving past already is is one
where you know the IC engineer is
primarily the one like writing the code
or generating it with tab complete um
and then review is is very much like a
process of of looking at every single
line of code like really careully
inspecting it. Um I think phase the
second phase that we're now you know
we're now entering or have entered is
one where um the job of engineering
feels more like you know an engineering
manager where you know you're you're
working with and orchestrating uh like a
team of agents that are going and
building they're handing you back
changes. You're you know you're
reviewing you're certainly reviewing the
code but a lot of it is is like
reviewing the you know the design docs
and the architecture and kind of the
higher level points. um still being able
to introspect into the code but uh you
know but a lot of that is happening of
the review like what you're looking for
is happening at a higher level of
abstraction u the the details there are
starting to be handled more by AI review
in in that world and then um I'd say the
third uh the third level which we have
not gotten to yet u but we'll you know I
think we will start to see if if
everything gets uh you know if
everything gets gets good enough is uh
one where I'd say that you it almost
looks more like work what working with
an external dev agency would be where
you're giving just highle specs u and
then you're getting back like the
artifact the finished product and um
you're reviewing that versus you may not
even ever necessarily look at the the
underlying code or or need to understand
it but um you're you're primarily
reviewing like the whatever that
finished product is and um I think we're
you know we're somewhere between like
phases one and two right now and then I
think uh in in the coming years we have
the opportunity to jump from two Three.